Jigar.vyas@hotmail.com

RESUME **CCNA, CCNP IP Routing** 



Fremont, California 94555

USA

Cell Number: 213-364-4028 : 408-507-9666

**Github Website** Linkedin

### **Career Statement**

13+ years of experience in diverse networks like Mobility Network, Enterprise Network and in Content Delivery Network with network design, implementation, troubleshooting, developing, POC for new network design and test it in lab environment before put it in production, and maintain network documentation and network automation.

#### **Technical Skills**

**Routers** Cisco routers (7600, 9000), Juniper Routers like, M320 and :

MX480, MX960, J4350, J6350, Arista 7200

**Switches** Cisco switches: - Layer 2 (2900 series), Layer 3 (3560, 3750, :

4500, 6500), juniper switches like EX4200, EX4500

**Network Management Tools** WhatsUp Gold, WANDL :

**Protocols/ Services** RIP, EIGRP, OSPF, BGP, TCP/IP, PPP, HDLC, Frame Relay, :

ATM, MPLS, L2VPN, L3VPN, IPSec, GRE, DMVPN, Multicasting

STP, VTP, HSRP/VRRP/GLBP, Basics of 802.1x

**Operating Systems** Windows, Linux :

Microsoft - VISIO, Power Point, Word **Reports Software Languages** : Python, Ansible, Flask, Django, Jinja2

**Packet Sniffers** WireShark, Etheral

#### **Employment History**

Edgio Inc. June 2022 -

**Present** 

Yahoo Inc. as Oath Holding Inc. Oct 2021 - June 2022 Mar 2016 - Sep 2021

Verizon Digital Media Services as Oath Holding Inc.

Job Title: Senior Network Engineer

- New network topology design and testing with either Juniper, Arista and or Cisco
- Understand user requirements and convert it into network designs and work to translate them into usable configuration
- Responsible for engineering spine and leaf fabric architecture networks, design, testing and implementation. VxLAN and its configuration on Juniper and Arista platform for datacenter redundancy with vendor redundancy
- Network automation using Python, Ansible/Napalm, Python Flask
- Build AWS Direct connect connection and put AWS VPCs traffic on it. Build VGW and TGW for AWS traffic redundancy in private network for AWS direct connect failover.

#### Jigar.vyas@hotmail.com

# RESUME **CCNA, CCNP IP Routing**



Fremont, California 94555

USA

Cell Number: 213-364-4028 : 408-507-9666

**Github Website** <u>Linkedin</u>

- Using streaming telemetry(gRPC, GNMI) and Telegraf monitor network traffic in monitoring tools like grafana, Kibana etc.
- Network/Data Center Technologies: Juniper Routers (M Series), on BGP OSPF and its ACLs for block and unblock the source and destinations IP based on the network/security requirement
- Configuring router for PoP bring up, circuit Turn ups and creates the LAB environment for testing as well.
- Work with NOC team for troubleshooting the network and customer problems
- Troubleshooting on BGP, OSPF of layer 3 and Layer 2 troubleshooting too
- Routing/Switching: Mx, EX and QFX series platform
- In few PoP Ciena as a backbone (Ciena 6500 and waveserver AI) and so configure the ciena device and ciena automation as well and add ciena in monitoring using GNMI

#### Rose International Inc. (USA)

Jan 2016 - Mar 2016

# **Client: California water works**

#### **Network Engineer**

- Network/Data Center Technologies: Cisco Routers (3900), Cisco Catalyst Switch, Cisco Nexus 5k and 7k Series, Port-Profiles, Routing and Service Profiles.
- Routing/Switching: WAN, LAN, TCP/IP, Spanning Tree, Frame-relay, PPP, Network Address Translation (NAT), Port Address Translation (PAT), Access Control List (ACL), RIP, OSPF, EIGRP, BGP, MPLS, VTP, SNMP, SMTP, Static Routing, VLAN
- Wireless Technologies: PoE, IEEE 802.1x & 802.11, WLAN, WAP, AP, SSID, Aironet.
- Monitoring/APPS: Solarwinds

#### **Vodafone West Ltd.**

Aug 2009 - Dec 2014

#### Sr. Engineer - Network Operation

- Worked on CISCO(ASR 9K,7600 series), Juniper Devices(J,M,Mx series). Also on CPE like Nortel, MROTEK, HP, Huawei routers.
- LAN/WAN network diagnose and troubleshoot on layer 1, 2, 3 problems and informed NOC team for corrective action (Worked with CISCO IOS & JUNIPER JUNOS)
- Responsible for delivery and O&M of Enterprise GGSN networks like Gn, Gy, Gi links.
- Timely site readiness, physical installation of PoP, acceptance test & commissioning of MPLS /Voice network PoP.
- Operation & maintenance of MPLS PoP of Core Enterprise & CEN network and meet customer
- Responsible for CISCO and JUNIPER RMA process till it's closer. TAC case status update till it's closer.
- Maintain Configuration, Documentation (VISIO's) and Records for Management
- IP backbone readiness for 10G and 100G link integration with DWDM Transport network. And also IP backbone up-gradation to support 100 gig links on the router.
- Distribution and access ring readiness on IP network for 1 gig link with DWDM transport network or on ECI MUX network.
- Performance, capacity & network change management of MPLS network.
- Handling the vendor team and ensuring the network & customer order execution within the timeline in coordination with all stakeholders.
- 3G core back born readiness as per corporate guide line for new roll out.

Jigar.vyas@hotmail.com

RESUME **CCNA, CCNP IP Routing** 



Fremont, California 94555

USA

Cell Number: 213-364-4028 : 408-507-9666

Manage spare & necessary tools for corrective maintenance

Linkedin

**Github Website** 

• Attended training session of OTJNR for juniper routers.

# **LOBO Staffing (Project : TATA Communication Ltd.)** L1 Data Engineer(wimax RF and IP Engineer)

January 2009 to August 2009

- Given Training on WIMAX Evolution & Network Overview in TATA Communication Ltd. Ahmedabad. Involve in Migration of Redwin ( MMDS ) to Wimax
- Execute the resolution of on-site faults as per SLA
- Responsible for Operations & Maintenance Performance of Core Network
- Troubleshoot the MPLS Network as well as Micro POP Locations of VSNL
- Routine health checkup of Wimax RF and Core Network and perform preventive action for that.
- Maintain VSNL NLD and ISP Rooms
- Traffic Analysis of all back bone links as well as other POPs of the VSNL
- Ensure the continuous availability of all data network services
- Working with Cisco routers and L3/L2 switches.
- Manage spares & necessary tools for corrective maintenance
- Coordinate with the vendor team to maintain the whole circuit for Wimax Network.
- Handle / Troubleshooting of MMDS Customers

# Telsima Communication Pvt. Ltd. **Network Operation & Maintenance**

Jan 2007 - Jan 2009

- In Recognition of excellent contribution in Phase II Deployment & O&M of Reliance Communication Wimax Project from Telsima Communication Pvt. Ltd.
- Involved in installation & commissioning (I & C), Pre-AT, AT of 50+ sites of Reliance in Gujarat.
- Maintenance of Reliance Communication's total 106 Wimax BSS.
- Troubleshooting and escalation of problems as per Severity.
- Worked on Cisco L2/L3 Switches when it was necessary.
- Traffic Analysis of Wimax back bone links and initiate it's up-gradation process accordingly.
- Worked with 802.16d Wimax technology.
- Manage spares & necessary tools for corrective maintenance
- I have done a cross check of RF Optimizing Data which comes in O&M Side.
- Physical Optimization from drive test reports like tilting, proper Orientation, Height reduction.
- Doing SS testing at the BTS side when related problems arise.

#### **Certification and Award**

- Successfully completed CISCO CCNA Certificate and, CCNP IP Routing
- In Recognition of excellent contribution in Phase II Deployment, O&M of Reliance Communication Wimax Project from Telsima Communication Pvt. Ltd.

#### **Education History**

#### Jigar.vyas@hotmail.com

Cell Number: 213-364-4028

: 408-507-9666

RESUME CCNA, CCNP IP Routing



Fremont, California 94555

USA

Github Website Linkedin

Jan-2015 To Dec-2015 MSEE at NPU, Fremont, California
June-2003 To June-2006 BEEC at SVMIT, Bharuch, Gujarat, India

• June-2001 To June-2003 Diploma in EC at B.S.Patel Polytechnic University, Mehsana, Gujarat,

India

### **Training**

- In networking project BGP routing between different AS and OSPF as IGP in GNS3.
- DMVPN, GRE over IPSec topology successfully implemented in GNS3.
- Completed Six Months of training at Doordarshan Kendra, Ahmedabad as a part of study curriculum during Diploma.
- Completed 4 week of training at Third Wave Exim (Computer networking and Hardware Solution), Ahmedabad as a part of vocational training during degree.

<u>Note:</u> I require sponsorship to work in the USA. My Current VISA status is H1B and have approved I140 in green card process.

**Declaration**: - I hereby declare that the above all information is true to the best of my Knowledge.